Guide to the William T. Miller papers, 1941-1992.
Miller, William T. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William T. Miller papers, 1941-1992.
14-8-3021
Miller, William T.(William Taylor),
10 cubic ft.
Correspondence, publications, research materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers, primarily relating to his research in fluorine chemistry, especially his work on the Manhattan Project at Columbia University. Also, files relating to the Cornell Chemistry Dept. and building projects in Baker Laboratory.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Chemistry, Cornell University.
William Miller received a B.S. and a Ph.D. from Duke University, and came to Cornell in 1936. During World War II, he worked at the S.A.M. Laboratories of the Manhattan Project at Columbia University on highly stable fluorocarbon polymers that would not react with uranium gas, thus making possible the separation of the fissionable isotope at Oak Ridge. After the war he returned to Cornell where he taught until his retirement in 1977. In 1974 he received the American Chemical Society award for Creative Work in Fluorine Chemistry, and in 1986 the French Moissan Centenary Medal in honor of Henri Moisson, who discovered the element fluorine in 1886. In addition to his teaching and research at Cornell, Miller was active in the planning of the new research wing of Baker Laboratory and in reconstructing the teaching laboratories in the building.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers, primarily relating to his research in fluorine chemistry, especially his work on the Manhattan Project at Columbia University. Also, files relating to the Cornell Chemistry Dept. and building projects in Baker Laboratory.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Miller, William T. 1911-1998.; Columbia University. S.A.M. Laboratory.; Cornell University. Department of Chemistry.; Manhattan Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
Fluorine.; Fluorocarbons.; Chemistry -- Study and teaching.; Chemical laboratories -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Early Alpha Files
Series II. Copies of Notebooks SAM
Series III. Early SAM
Series IV. SAM Files 1
Series V. Alpha Files - Cornell A-L
Series VI. Alpha Files - Cornell M-Z and Chemistry Department Newsletters
Series VII. Baker Lecture Correspondence and Cards from International Colleagues
Series VIII. Baker Lab Renovation Files and Reprints, Correspondence with Smithsonian
CONTAINER LIST
- Early Alpha Files
  - Letters to and from Samuel Aspinall, Technical Aide National Defense Committee (NDRC), Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bridgeman's Results - Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rc: (NDRC) Program Letters- Bush and Bowman, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters from P.W. Bridgeman -Explosion letter, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - P.W Bridgeman- S.A.M. Correspondence & Notes, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - P.W. Bridgeman S.A.M. Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carbide and Carbon chemicals Corporation- Program F C Res.S.A.M. Prep. For R.H Crist, 1945-04-30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - N.D.R.C Contract Between U.S. and Cornell University, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ralph Connor Letters, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters & Papers to and from Dr. J.B. Conant, G.H. Cady, and H.M. Chadwell, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from W.S. Calcott, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letter from George H. Cady, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters to and from R.D. Frowler and letter to Dr. Frank D. Fackenthal, pres. of Columbia University, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters to and from Capt. L.L. Grotjan Thompson Custody of Documents, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters from Secretary of Cornell University, To Dr. Grosse, Greene, From John Geherin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Re: History of Gaseous Diffusion Plant, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Program for Henne, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters from Stanford & P.J. Hanzlik, Hough, Hass, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Henne, Correspondence - War Period, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Henne, Letters - S.A.M. Program for Henne, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Includes Copies of WTMs reports to Marvvel, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fidelity and Casualty Company of New York, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Samples for Festers to Khavasch, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Plastometer tests, Letters to Mr. Bowers, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letters to and from C.S. Marvel, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - A.E.C Publicity Re: MFP, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Letters from the Office of Scientific Research and Development (Insurance), 1941 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Original Rating of O P M (AlA) for Project, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cornell work, 1942-10-1943-03 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Plax Corporation, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Swelling of MFP, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Phelan weekly reports, 1942-12-1943-02 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Letters to & from R. Rosen, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Report of Reaction on CClF=CClF, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Nov. '41 Formal Request from NDRC, Whitmore letter to J. B. Conant June '41, First Conf. At Cornell with Johnson, J.R., and Henne, 1941-11-1942 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - S.A.M Early Memos and Reports- Programs, Columbia: Permission for Caobide to use inventions at Hooker & Ninde, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Notes from Conferences, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - First Cornell NDRC Report, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Formal Reports - Henne and Miller, NDRC, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence re: Final Report and Patent Matters NDRC Contract, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Final Report on Fluorocarbons and more, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - NDRC Cornell Report- Illustrations- Negatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Columbia NDRC Reports, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Preliminary and Final Reports NDRC, Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Report B-178, Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - NDRC Reports from W.T.M.- Correspondence period. Letter reports, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - W.T.M's monthly NDRC Reports and Receipls, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Monthly Reports from other section Members, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Biweekly Reports and manuscripts, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Notes from S.A.M. Biweekly reports, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Columbia Biweekly repotts S.A.M., 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Biweekly reports S.A.M., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence between William Miller and various chemical companies, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Winslow - Weekly reports, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Ehrenfeld - Weekly reports, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Receipt forms for using classified material, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence between W.T.Miller, Winslow and Reed, work on FC's progressing at SAM and Cornell, 1943-03-1943-05 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Receipt - Suspeuse File, 1943-02 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Compounds Prepared, Cornell - Properties, 1942-07 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Declorination, 1943-03 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - The reaction of Horine with Tetrafluoroethylene, 1943-03 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Report on C-3, 1943-03 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Notes on Polymerization of Perfluorobutadiene, Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Processes Developed MFL Data, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Record of visits to project from Allen, Contacts with Winde, Hooker, etc., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Material from S.A.M Permanent Custody, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Plastic Flows Distortion Recovery Tests on M.F.P. By Donald Keel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Tensile Strength Properties of M.F.P., by Donald Keel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Tests on MFW and MFP, Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Density, Refractive index, Traus. Temp., Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Omnibus Case, nd., Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - S.A.M. Notebook References, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Re: Plastic and W.T.M.- Hist. & Devel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Omnibus Specification, Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - SAM 329c. File Inventory from D.Evans, Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - A.E.C. I FBI Security, Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Purification of Special Chemical 539, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Polymer products Intermediate molecular Weight, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Polymetization of Perhals Olefins other than 359 (prober), Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Reports on Physical Constants Cornell, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dittman's Thesis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Physical Propeities of Compounds, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Haloperoxides, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Polymerization of 539 (Maymard), Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Peroxides and Polymerization, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Polymerization of 539 (Dittman), Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - SAM Personal, Incomplete - ( security?), Group3B-1 Names, addresses and phone numbers, 1944-10-05 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Publicity Releases, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Replacement of Ce by F, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Reed Old Reports, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sample Identification, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Solids Fluorination of (C4F6)n, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Stability of Fluorocarbons, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Swelling ofMFP by Solvents, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Thermocouple Calibration Valves, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Thermal Polymerization, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The1modynamics of Fluorocarbons, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Tehafluoroethylene Polymer, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Thmmal Cracking, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Thermal Depolymerization, Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Uses K-25, Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Report outline; notes etc., Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Instructions for Authors, SAM Treatise, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Compounds, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - MFP Physical Properties, Heat Treatment (Ross), 1945 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Useful Processes in Fluorocarbon Chemistry, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Physical Properties- Trifluorochloroethyleno, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - MFP Production, Winde, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Physical Properties of MFL (Jacobson), Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Plasticity & Distortion Recav. MFP, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Program Ideas, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Plasticization (Keel), Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Molding of MFP, Undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - S.A.M. Biweekly Reports to W.T.M., Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - M.W. Kellogg re Kel-F, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Properties of Kel-F, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - DuPortt re Teflon, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Veloform, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Brown Package - Map, Smyth Report Original Issue, Hookers "E" Award, Books about a-bomb, News paper heading Sept. 1949 about the explosions of the a-bomb, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Chapter 32- Preparation of Fluorocarbons by Polymerization of Olefins by: William T. Miller, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Two Record Books With notes from Miller, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Copies of Notebooks SAM
  - H.M. Haedler, 1943-02-19-1947 (Box 3)
    Notebook #555
  - Elloit Charney, 1947-03-13 (Box 3)
    Notebook #556
  - Wyle Hats, Donald Stewart, 1943-05-06 (Box 3)
    Notebook #557
  - Albert Myerson, 1943-01-07 (Box 3)
    Notebook #560
  - F.H. Winslow, 1945-09 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3367
  - W.R. Lake, Undated (Box 3)
    Notebook #2441
  - B.J. Samuels, 1943-11-10 (Box 3)
    Notebook #1116
  - F.H. Winslow, 1945-02-01 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3365
  - J.M. Phelan, 1945-02-20 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3520
  - J.M. Phelan, 1943-04 (Box 3)
    Notebook #562
  - John Maynard, 1944-06-02 (Box 3)
    Notebook #1813
  - M. Prokev, 1943-05 (Box 3)
    Notebook #470
  - Ehrenfeld, 1943-04 (Box 3)
    Notebook #33
  - Ehrenfeld, 1945-02-07 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3327
  - A.L. Dittman, 1945-02 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3331
  - A.L. Dittman, 1943-07-30 (Box 3)
    Notebook #546
  - S.K. Reed, 1945-02-06 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3519
  - S.K. Reed, 1943-09-08 (Box 3)
    Notebook #559
  - Walter Pocock, 1944-03-23 (Box 3)
    Notebook #1583
  - G. Ganlin, 1944-09-07 (Box 3)
    Notebook #2182
  - G. Ganlin, 1943-09 (Box 3)
    Notebook #563
  - Pearl Foster, 1943-11-18 (Box 3)
    Notebook #1127
  - Pearl Foster, 1943-11-18 (Box 3)
  - Pearl Foster, 1944-08-07 (Box 3)
    Notebook #2016
  - D.K. Keel, 1945-09-06 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3206
  - D.K. Keel, 1945-04-13 (Box 3)
  - M. Prober, 1945-02 (Box 3)
    Notebook #471
  - M. Prober, 1944-04-17 (Box 3)
    Notebook #1651
  - M. Prober, 1943-04 (Box 3)
  - O.A. Blum, 1943-11-02 (Box 3)
    Notebook #1080
  - HR. Davis, 1945-02-01 (Box 3)
    Notebook #3518
  - Correspondence re: report, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Prober, Correspondence re: report, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Butadienes (Chiaro) Gaulius work, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Methods of Volving, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Analysis of Oil for Unsaturatioh, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brockways Report, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Comments on Bromination, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - To Miller from Reed, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Tests by Keel, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chlorination, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chemical Properties, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Copolymers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Dehalogenation, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Diffusion Process Record, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ruorination- Vapor Phase, Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fluorocarbon Oils - General, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Friedel and Craft type Catalyzed Polymerization, Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Fluorination- Liquid Phase, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - MFL Preparation, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Tables for MFL Reports, Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - MFL- Distillation Curves - Miscellaneous data, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Solubility in Fluorocarbons, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - MFL Report- Prober's, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - MFL Properties, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - MFL Report, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - MFP, Undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Oxygen Reactions, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Oxygen Polymerization, Undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Pyralysis of 539- Hot Tube work, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Pyralysis (Other than 539), 1945 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Early SAM
  - Variety, 1956 (Box 4)
    Notebook #45
  - Envelopes with letters, Undated (Box 4)
    Notebook #47
  - Horace Davis, 1944-04-19 (Box 4)
    Notebook #1657
  - B.J. Samuels, 1944-09 (Box 4)
    Notebook #2191
  - Smith, 1943-12-16 (Box 4)
    Notebook #1196
  - D.C. Blue, 1944-02-03 (Box 4)
    Notebook #1386
  - Murray Hauptscheir, 1945-02-01 (Box 4)
    Notebook #3514
  - Murray Hauptscheir, 1943-12 (Box 4)
    Notebook #1188
  - Don H. Stewart, 1943-07-19 (Box 4)
    Notebook #456
  - Thelma Borders, 1945-06 (Box 4)
    Notebook #?
  - Zimmerman, 1944-02-03 (Box 4)
    Notebook #1385
  - Zimmerman, 1944-02-03 (Box 4)
- SAM Files 1
  - The Nicholas H. Noyes Collection of historical America in the Cornell University Library, 1996-09-06 (Box 5)
  - Grad. Study in Chern.- Bulletin, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - SAM Programs, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Contacted at SAM Carbide Kellex Army etc., Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - SAM notebook references, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - First Agreement With Government, Supplement Agreement With Government, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Army Contract for Writing Final Report, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Patent Agreement With Cornell, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Cornell during Way Period Salary etc., 1942-1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Carbide - SAM, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re: Gov't Agreement - Patents Lavender, Anderson (Cornell Certification), 1945 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lister - SAM, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - SAM Research Programs, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Amer. Cyanamid Co.- Agreement re: SA.No. 743,455 (WTM) and U.S. 2,497,046 (Kropa), 1952 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University - SAM, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Memo to J.R. Johnson, A.L. Henne, C.S. Marvel, Proposed methods for the Synthesis of Compounds of the type CnF2n+2, 1941-10-02 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The Baker Laboratory of Chemistry, by: Louis m. Dennis, Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Debye, Biographical, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Prof. P. Debye, Undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Bismuth Compounds, Stanford, Hanslik, 1935-1940 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Reference Material re: Fluorocarbon Devel, and Diffusion Plant. Biographies - Notes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Re: Manhattan Project, Fluorocarbon, SAM Labs., Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - WTM - History of Fluorocarbon Development for the Manhattan Project., Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Clippings re; Fluorocarbons etc.., Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - News Items re: Diffusion Plant, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Oak Ridge - U-235 Process, Undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Harold Goedwhite re: WWII account of CF research for bombs' book (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Geo. C. Caldwell, First Head of Chern. Dept., Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Inquiries, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - MFL Test Sharp of Kellex to M. Benedict, 1945-12-07 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Some Prelim Drawings for Chap.32 (Cornell Report), Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Ptints from Final SAM Report, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - NDRC Prints for Report, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Oak Ridge Diffusion Plant and Atomic Bomb Explosion, Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - SAM photos, Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - SAM Glasswave. Specially constructed E-O oxygen- Evee System E-9, Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Letter from Bridgeman talking about an explosion and more, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Pictures of Prof. Miller, 1941-1949 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Notebook References from Co Workers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Weekly Reports from Co Workers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Index for Cornell notebooks, Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Photostats of notebook records RE: Fluorine Sensitized Oxidation and Chlorination, Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Notes from Foster or Barber, Undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Black, Notes from others working on the project - Book, Undated (Box 5)
  - 3514 - Factory Data, 1945-02-01 (Box 5)
  - 3494 - E.W. Fagen Library Work, Undated (Box 5)
    Notebook #3494
  - 3515 - Oscar Blum, 1945-02-01 (Box 5)
    Notebook #3515
  - 3574 - H.S. Schick, 1945-02-03 (Box 5)
    Notebook #3574
  - 961 - Thelma Borders, Undated (Box 5)
    Notebook #961
  - 3729 - K. Keel, 1946-02 (Box 5)
    Notebook #3729
  - Red with notes from WTM - Book, Undated (Box 5)
  - 3332 - Sample Book, Undated (Box 5)
    Notebook #3332
  - Program and Ideas, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Red record book with notes from WTM - Book, Undated (Box 5)
  - F.E. Winslow, Undated (Box 5)
  - Barber, Undated (Box 5)
    Notebook #25
- Alpha Files - Cornell A-L
  - Am. Chern. Society including Division of Organic Chemistry, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - A's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Univ. Archives, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Paul D. Bartlett, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - H.C. Brown, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dr. L.A. Bigelow, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Burton's nomination for F- Chern. Award, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Don J. Burton, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - B's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hans Bethe, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Jon Clardy, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - David Carson, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Richard D. Chambers, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Rudolf Criege, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cumulative Exams W.T.M., Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - W.D. Cooke, Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Orville Chapman, Undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Bany K. Carpenter, Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - David B. Collum, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - C's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Dr. R.D. Dresdner, Undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - William P. Daily, Undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - D's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - PeterDebye, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Phil Eaton, Undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Prof. H. J. Emeleus, Univ. of Cambridge, London, Eng., Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Greg Ezra, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - R.E. Ehrenfeld, Cornell Council, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - E's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Simon and Sibyl Freed, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Award for Creative Work in Fluorine chemistry, Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Sven Fischer, Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Michael E. Fisher, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Ruorine Symposium- Estes Park Colorado, 1962-07-17-1962-07-20 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Award for Ruorine Chemistry, ACS, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Robert Filler, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Frechet, John, Undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Directory of Members, Div. Of Fluorine Chern. ACS, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Ruorine Division, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Paul Flory's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - F's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Bruce Ganum, Undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Paul M. Gross, Undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Henry Gilman, Undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Bob Geyer, Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - W. H. Gumprecht, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Thomas F. Gieryn, Sociologist from W. of Indiana, Bloomington, Undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - G's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Paul A. Hartman, Physic's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - W.H. Hawkins re: Kaufmann biography, Undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Fume Hood Measurements, Undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Prof. Rolf Huisgen, Undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Roald Hoffmann, Undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Dr. A.L. Henne, Undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Hi gil School Project re: F.-Chem., Undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Edgar Heilbronner, Undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - R.N. Haszeldine, Undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Hist. Of Chern., Undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - J.L. Hoard, Chemicals Supplied, Undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - R.E. Hughes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Paul Houston, Undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - H's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Gordon Hammes, Undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Robert A. Hill, Mgr. External Relations, Undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - C.K. Ingold, Undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - International Union of Chern., Zurich Conference IUC, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - India, S.K. Nema, G.N. Mather, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Keith Johnson, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Isoflurane, Harold Jaffe, Undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Edward G. Jefferson, Undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - J.R. Johnson, Undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - J's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Atsuo Kuki, Undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - KING, Ed. L. Editor Inorganic Chemistry, Undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - K's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Ralph landau, Undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - F.A. Long, Undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Lectnres, Undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Harry Levin, Dean of Arts College, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - W.F. Libby, Undated (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Peter Jansbury, Undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - L's, Undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
- Alpha Files - Cornell M-Z and Chemistry Department Newsletters
  - Fred McLafferty, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fred McLafferty, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Walter C. McGroves, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Me's, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Donna Middleton, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - E. Pat Mundy III - Sci. Historian, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - President Deane W. Malott, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Earl L. Muetterties, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - C.S. Marvel, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Muxfeldl, Hans, Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Jerrold Meinwald, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - W.T.Miller- Copy for Grad. Bulletin, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Edward C. Mal by, Jr.- Dean G Vet College, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Research Program - W.T.M., Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - M's, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Nobel Prize Announcement, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)